Over 200 claims were denied by the insurer,
even though it had been collecting premiums.
The US Department of Labor has accused Prudential
Financial of illegally denying
over 200 life insurance claims,
even after the insurer had continued to
collect premiums from the policyholder.
This is only the most recent instance of a rash of
insurers denying claims customers have paid for.
A number of life insurance companies
have been found to be denying claims
made on policies that have been paid for years.
Many employers include supplemental life plans
as a part of their employee benefits
packages. This makes it possible for
employees to pay an additional premium
for the coverage out of their paychecks.
Prudential of Newark, New Jersey has reached a
settlement with the US government with respect
to what is called “evidence of insurability.
” This is a common underwriting practice for
supplemental life contracts. It requires
an employee to complete a form that shows
that they are in good health before the
start of the employer-sponsored coverage.
Life insurance premiums have been paid by many
employees for years without completing the form.
The settlement detailed how Prudential had
been collecting premiums for some of the
participants in these employee
plans for years – in some cases
since 2004 – even though that evidence of
insurability form had never been completed.
Prudential had been denying any
claims between 2017 and 2020 that
did not have the evidence of the
insurability form completed even
though it still collected premiums from
the customer since initial enrollment.
The settlement with the US government requires
Prudential to pay out life insurance claims
regardless of the presence of
evidence of insurability form,
as long as it had been collecting premiums
for that customer. This, according to a
statement from the Department of Labor.
The Department of Labor has reached similar
settlements with other insurers for similar
reasons. In 2021, it settled with United of
Omaha Life Insurance, which had been denying
claims payments even after the customer had
been paying premiums for years. In 2022,
Reliance Standard Life Insurance came to
a similar settlement for a similar reason
with the Eighth Circuit Court of Appeals, which
ruled in favor of a widower who sued the insurer.
Thank you for following L I N!
Make sure, to hit subscribe,
and sign up for our weekly newsletter today!